4projects.com 2012-08-23

# 4Projects > Home

Website & Email Privacy Policy

4Projects are committed to safeguarding the privacy of our website visitors; this policy sets out how we will treat your personal information.

**(1) What information do we collect?**

We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:

(a) information about your computer and about your visits to and use of this website (including your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit, entry & exit points and number of page views;

(b) information relating to any transactions carried out between you and us on or in relation to this website, including information relating to any purchases you make of our goods or services;

(c) information that you provide to us for the purpose of registering with us (including Name, Company, Job Title, Email, Address, Telephone & mobile number);

(d) information that you provide to us for the purpose of subscribing to our website services, email notifications and/or newsletters (including opens, clicks, preference information, email and other contact information);

(e) any other information that you choose to send to us;

**(2) Cookies**

A cookie consists of information sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser on your computer. This information is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the web server. This enables the web server to identify and track the usage of the website in question..

4Projects may use both “session” cookies and “persistent” cookies on their websites. We will use the session cookies to keep track of you whilst you navigate the website. We will use the persistent cookies to enable our website to recognise you when you visit;

Session cookies will be deleted from your computer when you close your browser. Persistent cookies will remain stored on your computer until deleted, or until they reach a specified expiry date.

4Projects makes use of Google Analytics to analyse the use of their websites. Google Analytics generates statistical and other information about website use by means of cookies, which are stored on users' computers. The information generated in this manner is used to create reports about the usage of 4Projects web sites, the use of Google Analytics also allows 4Projects to monitor system performance and can be used to identify areas that can be improved.  Google will store this information securely; their privacy policy is available at:[ http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html](http://www.google.com/privacypolicy.html).

With the onset of the EU Cookie law, 4Projects operates on the precept of implied consent.  Rather than explicitly asking each individual user to accept the storing of cookies, this means that continued usage of any 4Projects website implies an acceptance to allow the storage of cookies as detailed within this policy.  For more information about the Cookie law and how it pertains to organisations please refer to the Information Commissioners website available [here](http://www.ico.gov.uk/for_organisations/privacy_and_electronic_communications/the_guide/cookies.aspx).

Most browsers allow you to reject all cookies, whilst some browsers allow you to reject just third party cookies. For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookies by clicking “Tools”, “Internet Options”, “Privacy”, and selecting “Block all cookies” using the sliding selector. Blocking all cookies will, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites, including this one.

**  (3) Using your personal data**

Personal data submitted on this website will be used for the purposes specified in this privacy policy or in relevant parts of the website.

We may use your personal information to:

(a) administer the website;

(b) improve your browsing experience by personalising the website;

(c) enable your use of the services available on the website;

(d) send you general (non-marketing) commercial communications;

(e) send you email notifications which you have specifically requested;

(f) send to you our newsletter and other marketing communications relating to our business or the businesses of carefully-selected third parties which we think may be of interest to you by post or, where you have specifically agreed to this, by email or similar technology (you can inform us at any time if you no longer wish to receive marketing communications);

(g) provide third parties with statistical information about our users –this information will not be used to identify individual users in any way;

(h) deal with enquiries and complaints made by or about you pertaining to the use of the website;

(i) OTHER USES.

Where you submit personal information for publication on our website, we will publish and otherwise use that information in accordance with the license you grant to us.

We will not without your express consent provide your personal information to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing.

**(4) Disclosures**

We may disclose information about you to any of our employees, officers, agents, suppliers or subcontractors insofar as reasonably necessary for the purposes as set out in this privacy policy.

In addition, we may disclose information about you:

(a) to the extent that we are required to do so by law;

(b) in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings;

(c) in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk).

Except as provided in this privacy policy, 4Projects will not provide your information to third parties.

**(5) International data transfers**

Information that we collect may be stored, processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this privacy policy.

Information which you provide may be transferred to countries (including the United States, Japan, Australia, and Canada which do not have data protection laws equivalent to those in force in the European Economic Areas (EEA).

In addition, personal information that you submit for publication on the website may be published on the internet and as such may be available, via the internet, around the world.

You expressly agree to such transfers of personal information.

**(6) Security of your personal data**

4Projects will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information.

We will store all the personal information you provide on our secure (password- and firewall- protected) servers.

It should be noted that data transmission carried out over the internet is inherently insecure, and as such 4Projects cannot guarantee the security of data sent via that route.

You are responsible for keeping your password and user details confidential. 4Projects will never ask you for your password for any reason.

**(7) Email policy overview**

4Projects maintains a strict opt-in only policy in regard to its email communications. We only send email to individuals who have requested that these mailings be sent to them, or as part of an on-going relationship we have with an individual or business.

Your right to control what mailings, if any, you receive from 4Projects is important to us. The information below will assist you in understanding the different mailing options you have, and how you can notify us of changes in the mailings you wish to receive or to unsubscribe in general.

Though we may include announcements from partners or other third parties in some communications, we do not provide email addresses to third parties.

If you believe you have received unwanted, unsolicited email sent via any 4Projects system or purporting to be sent via 4Projects, please forward a copy of that email with your comments to [info@4projects.com](mailto:info@4projects.com)  for review and subsequent actioning.

(a) What mailing lists 4Projects maintains and your subscription options

**Customer, partner & prospect mailing lists**

_Newsletter_  
Keep up to date with what is happening with our newsletter showcasing webinars, whitepapers, articles, research, case studies and best practice guides.

**Customer and partner only mailing lists**

_Platform Updates_  
News on the latest developments and new features of the 4Projects platform..

_Service Update_  
Details of critical service and performance issues with the 4Projects platform. These communications will be infrequent.

To sign up to our email communications please visit: [www.4projects.com](http://www.4projects.com/).

**Other email notifications**

_Transactional emails_  
4Projects typically sends an automated email confirmation when a form is completed requesting information.

**Customer support incidents and responses**  
Responses to customer support or pre-sales support requests are handled through email, telephone or online chat.

(b) Changing your subscription preferences

**4Projects mailing lists**

**Customer and partner communications**  
As a 4Projects customer or partner, you can update your communications preferences at any time by following the links located at the bottom of our emails. Requests submitted in this manner are generally processed and effective immediately.

In addition, you may email a request to [info@4projects.com](mailto:info@4projects.com) requesting that your address be unsubscribed. Please be aware that unsubscribe requests submitted in this manner will take longer to process and will not be effective immediately.

**Non-customer communications**  
As a web site visitor who has requested that we send you email updates, you can update your communications preferences or unsubscribe at any time by clicking on the relevant link within emails you receive from us. Unsubscribe requests submitted in this manner are processed and effective immediately.

In addition, you may email a request to [info@4projects.com](mailto:info@4projects.com) requesting that your address be unsubscribed. Please be aware that unsubscribe requests submitted in this manner will take longer to process and will not be effective immediately.

**Transactional emails**  
You will only receive transactional emails from 4Projects when you request information. There is no need to unsubscribe from these one-time mailings.

**Customer support incidents and responses**  
You will only receive these email responses in reply to specific support requests, or in response to technical issues detected by 4Projects proactive monitoring. There is no need to unsubscribe from these interactive mailings.

(c) Third party mailings

Occasionally, we may contract with a third party to communicate on 4Projects behalf to the third party's contacts. We do not collect your email address or contact information from this third party, and we do not have access to their mailing list.

Depending on the nature of the third party mailing, we may, in order to comply with applicable laws, provide the third party with a suppression list of contacts to exclude from their list. The third party does not have permission to keep or market to this list, or to use it in any way other than as a suppression list for a mailing they are providing on 4Projects behalf.

(d) Sharing and Usage

4Projects will never share, sell, or rent individual personal information with anyone for their promotional use without your advance permission or unless ordered by a court of law. Information submitted to us is only available to employees managing this information for purposes of contacting you or sending you emails based on your request for information, and to contracted service providers for purposes of providing services relating to our communications with you.

(e) Email Tracking

When we send you emails, we may include a tacking image and web analytics code to allow us to determine the number of people who have interacted with our emails. When you click on a link in an email, we may record this individual response to allow us to customise our offerings to you. This tracking collects only limited information such as webpage viewed, time and date.

**(8) Policy amendments**

We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our websites. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes.

We may also notify you of changes to our privacy policy by email.

**(9) Your rights**

You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you. Provision of such information may be subject to the payment of a fee (currently fixed at £10.00).

You may instruct us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes by email at any time. (In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal data for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of the use of your personal data for marketing purposes.)

**(10) Third party websites**

4Projects websites may contain links to other websites. 4Projects are not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of third party websites.

**(11) Updating information**

Please let us know if the personal information we hold about you needs to be corrected or updated.

**(12) Contact**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal data, please write to us by email to [info@4projects.com](mailto:info@4projects.com)  or by post to 4Projects, The Teleport, Doxford International, Sunderland, SR3 3XD.

**(13) Data controller**

The data controller responsible for our website is 4Projects, contactable via email to [info@4projects.com](mailto:info@4projects.com).

Our data protection registration number is **Z9988339.**
